scanlife.com 2019-12-29

# None

## Effective Date: October 3, 2019

**Privacy Policy**

Scanbuy understands that privacy is important to you.  This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) explains how personal information about you is collected, used and may be disclosed by Scanbuy.  This Policy applies to information we collect when you use our websites, the ScanLife application, the Scanbuy code resolution platform and other online products and services where this Policy is posted (collectively, the "Services").  Please take the time to read through the Policy carefully, so that you can make informed choices concerning your personal information and can better protect your privacy and security.

Scanbuy reserves the right to change this Policy from time to time.  Be sure to check this page periodically for updates.  If Scanbuy makes any changes to this Policy, we will notify you by changing the “Effective Date” listed.  If Scanbuy makes any significant or substantial changes to this Policy, we will obtain your express consent prior to your continued use of the Services. Please be advised that failure to consent may result in the Services not functioning properly or not functioning at all.

**I.  Securing your data**

Scanbuy will take reasonable technical and organizational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information.

Scanbuy will store all the personal information you provide on secure servers.

Information relating to electronic transactions entered into via this website will be protected by encryption technology.

**No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100 percent secure. While Scanbuy uses reasonable efforts to protect your information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure, Scanbuy cannot guarantee its absolute security.**

**Please consider carefully before disclosing any personal information.**

**II. Personal Information  **  
Scanbuy collects personal information that you provide to us.  For example, we collect information when you create an account or a profile, configure your preferences, and when you email, text, call, or otherwise communicate with us. 

The types of personal information we may collect include: your ScanLife Account User ID, mobile phone number, email address, account information, age, gender demographic information, information about your preferences and any other information you affirmatively provide to us (for example, as part of a message you send to us). 

Scanbuy may be able to collect location based information, such as GPS data, if you have such a phone feature enabled and have provided us with permission to collect such information. ScanLife, upon installation on your mobile device, will provide you with an opportunity to give permission to collect such location based information. If you subsequently choose to stop Scanbuy’s collection of location based information, you can adjust your preferences on your mobile device settings for the ScanLife mobile application.

**Please consider carefully before disclosing any personal information.**

**III. Automatically Collected Information**  
Scanbuy collects certain types of non-personally identifiable information whenever you use ScanLife.  For example, when you access ScanLife, some information such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address, Internet service provider, operating system, the service from which you arrived, the page you requested, the time and date of your visit, and potentially other site usage statistics will be collected automatically as part of the software processes of the web page.  For mobile devices, we collect information regarding the type of mobile device you use, your mobile device’s unique device ID, the IP address of your mobile device, your mobile operating system, applications installed on the device, your use of those applications, the type of mobile Internet browser you use when accessing products and services, and anonymous information about the way you use our Services; we may share and allow our third party partners to share this non-identifying information with other third parties that perform targeted advertising activities across other apps and websites. Scanbuy collects your IP address to identify the country in which you are using ScanLife in order to provide you with the most relevant information in response to your requests.

The foregoing information itself does not personally identify you, but could potentially be linked with personal information that you provide us.  These statistics allow Scanbuy to analyze the effectiveness of its website and software applications and make improvements where needed. Upon installation on your device, we will provide you with an opportunity to consent to the collection, use and disclosure of such non-personally identifiable information as described in this policy generally and in the Use and Disclosure section in particular. Please note that such non-personally identifiable information may be required in order for the Services to function properly. Please see  **Data Retention Policy; Managing Your Information; Opt-out Rights**  below to review your choices regarding your information.

**IV. Cookies Persistent Device Identifiers, Advertising Identifiers and Other Technologies**

Scanbuy, along with our third party service partners and business partners, use cookies, Web beacons, persistent device identifiers (e.g. Android ID), advertising identifiers (e.g. Google’s “Advertising ID,” Apple’s “IDFA”) and other technologies. These technologies are used for tracking, advertising, analytics and personalization and optimization of the Services. The information collected through these technologies may not necessarily correlate to the information described in the Automatically Collected Information section above.

  1. Cookies. A Cookie is a string of information that a website saves on a visitor’s computer or mobile device and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website operator each time the visitor returns.  Merchant partner will place a cookie or similar technology on visitor's device when an ad is clicked.

  * Persistent cookies remain on the visitor’s computer or mobile device after the browser has been closed.
  * Session cookies exist only during a visitor’s online session and disappear from the visitor’s computer or mobile device when they close the browser software.

  1. Persistent Device Identifiers. Persistent device identifiers are unique strings that are associated with the mobile device that you use to connect to the Services. Persistent device identifiers may be modified or disabled by sophisticated users. Some persistent device identifiers can only be reset by wiping the entire device.
  2. Advertising Identifiers. Advertising identifiers (e.g. Google’s “Advertising ID,” Apple’s “IDFA”) are unique strings associated with your mobile device provided by the operating system. Advertising identifiers may be modified or disabled by users in the operating system settings. See the Do Not Track section for more information about how to configure these settings.

Scanbuy uses the Cookies and similar technologies to assign you an anonymous user ID, retain your preferences and account settings, and learn about your possible interests so that we can personalize and improve our Services. You have the ability to delete or disable browser cookies through your browser. Choices made are browser and device specific. Please refer to your browser’s technical information for instructions on how to delete or disable cookies and other tracking technologies.

**V. Do Not Track**

Apple iOS and Google Android devices provide the ability for users to enable a “do not track” setting that disables your advertising identifier. If the “do not track” setting is disabled, we may record when a user installs the App. We may also run targeted advertising on third party applications via our advertising display partners. For users who have enabled the “do not track” setting in iOS or Android, this data will not be collected.

Please note that the “do not track” setting may not be available on all operating systems or versions of ScanLife. The “do not track” settings require iOS 6 or later, or Android 2.3 or later.  **In order for the “do not track” settings to function on ScanLife, you must have a version of ScanLife installed which is up to date as of the effective date of this Policy.**

**To enable the “do not track” setting on iOS, visit:**  <http://support.apple.com/kb/HT4228>

**To enable the “do not track” setting on Android please perform the following steps:** (i) Open your ‘ **Settings** ’ app; (ii) Locate **Privacy** ; (iii) Select ‘ **Advanced** ’; (iv) Select ‘ **Ads** ’; (v) Select ‘ **Opt out of Ads Personalization** ’; and (vi) When prompted select ‘ **Ok** ’.

For additional details on option out of ads personalization for your Google account, visit the following external link: [Opt out of seeing personalized ads](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en)

Scanbuy may update these instructions periodically as new information becomes available from Apple, Google, and other Operating System manufacturers.

**VI. Anonymous & Aggregate Information  
**Scanbuy collects some information on an anonymous basis. Scanbuy may also anonymize some personal information so that it cannot be readily used to personally identify an individual user. Scanbuy obtains aggregate information by combining anonymous information that meet certain criteria into groups. Scanbuy may share aggregate or anonymous information in various formats with our users and partners, and may work with our partners to do research to improve the products and services we provide where needed.

**VII. Use and Disclosure**  
In accordance with your choices made upon installation on your device, you agree that Scanbuy may access, preserve, and disclose your information in connection with your use of the Application or if required to do so by law or in a good faith belief that such access, preservation or disclosure is reasonably necessary to: (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, (b) enforce a Terms & Conditions of Use agreement, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues (including, without limitation, the filtering of spam), (d) respond to user support requests, or (e) protect the rights, property or safety of Scanbuy, its users, and the public.

**Scanbuy uses the personal information we collect to process your requests, provide online services, provide marketing communications, maintain service quality, to perform data matching and understand your needs so that we can provide you with the highest quality of service.   You may also receive administrative emails from Scanbuy related to the primary usage of ScanLife; you may not opt-out of administrative emails.**  **We may also share personal information with third parties who complete transactions or perform services on our behalf.   These third parties will be required to treat your information in accordance with our privacy policies.**

Scanbuy may also share aggregate level and/or anonymous information with our customers and/or partners for interest-based advertising.   **Scanbuy does not share personally identifiable information with our partners, restricting the disclosure to location information, sex, age and other anonymous and/or aggregate level data.**

For users in North America, Scanbuy may share your device’s precise geolocation, such as GPS data, if you have such a phone feature enabled and have provided us with permission to collect such information, as well as other details about your device (like hardware characteristics, a variety of sensor data, and a list of installed third-party applications) with our partner Sense360 on an ongoing basis, including when the apps are closed. This information is sent with the device’s advertising identifier or another unique device-specific code. Sense360 may use all of this information for market research and other research regarding aggregated patterns, and as further described in its Privacy Policy, which has more detail on the entire process. For example, Sense360 analyzes restaurant visit trends to better serve its customers’ needs. You can use your device settings to (i) disable or limit precise geolocation collection for the entire device (which will affect some device functionality) or just particular apps (which may affect the functionality of this app) and/or (ii) disable or limit use of the advertising identifier (which will block that identifier’s transmission to Sense360). **To view inMarket’s Privacy Policy, visit** **<https://sense360.com/privacy-policy/>** **.**

Scanbuy may use third party service providers and business partners to perform functions in connection with the Services. Scanbuy may share information about you that they need to perform their functions, but they may not use it for other purposes. **IN ACCORDANCE WITH YOUR CHOICES MADE UPON INSTALLATION ON YOUR DEVICE, YOU CONSENT TO THE DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION FROM YOU AND ABOUT YOU AS DESCRIBED ABOVE AND HEREIN.**

Scanbuy works with third parties to collect certain non-identifying information about your interests, including aggregate level and/or anonymous information, to provide targeted advertising and analytics services on our site or within our application, or across other sites and other applications. These entities may use technologies to collect information about your use of our mobile applications, including device attributes such as: operating system, hardware version, device settings, IP address, time zone, device carrier, applications installed on the device, and device advertising identifiers. We may share and allow our third party partners to share this non-identifying information with other third parties that perform targeted advertising activities across other apps and websites. Please see  **Data Retention Policy; Managing Your Information; Opt-out Rights**  below to review your choices regarding your information.

Data collected from a particular device may be used on a different device that is linked to the device on which the data was originally collected. Any choice made by you regarding Scanbuy’s collection of data on one device will be reflected on the other device(s) linked to that device. **Please consider carefully before making any choices regarding Scanbuy’s collection of data.**

If Scanbuy becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, sale of assets, joint venture, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, liquidation, dissolution, or other transaction or if the ownership of all or substantially all of our business otherwise changes, we may share or transfer your information to a third party or parties in connection therewith.

Scanbuy may also share your information with our affiliates for purposes consistent with this Policy. Our affiliates will be required to maintain that information in accordance with this Policy.

Scanbuy may combine all of the information collected from or about you and use it in the manner described in this Policy. 

Scanbuy may share aggregated and anonymized information relating to users of the Services with affiliated or unaffiliated third parties.

If you have any questions or concerns with respect to this Policy, you may contact us at **[privacy@scanbuy.com](mailto:privacy@scanbuy.com)** **.**

**VIII. Data Retention Policy, Managing Your Information, Opt-out Rights**  
Scanbuy retains automatically collected information as well user provided data.  Please see **Transparency and Choice** below to learn how you can access your information, and how you can update, amend or delete your information. Please note that some of your information may be required in order for the Services to function properly.

Information collected by Scanbuy in connection with your use of our products and services may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Scanbuy maintains facilities.  Accordingly, your use of ScanLife, or any other products or services provided, grants Scanbuy permission to transfer such information to other Scanbuy facilities which may be outside of your country.  “Processed,” means using Cookies, or similar technology, on a computer or mobile device or using information in any way, including, but not limited to, collecting, storing, deleting, using, combining and disclosing information.

You can stop the collection of information by ScanLife by uninstalling the application.  You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network. Information collected by Scanbuy in connection with your use of our products or services may be held onto after you are no longer a customer.

Scanbuy may also share aggregate level and/or anonymous information with our customers and/or partners.   **Scanbuy does not share personally identifiable information with our partners, restricting the disclosure to location information, sex, age and other anonymous and/or aggregate level data.  **Scanbuy provides an opt-out tool which is cookie based. **If you’d like to opt-out of Scanbuy’s use of your aggregate level and/or anonymous information, outside of use that is required for the Services to function properly, please visit the link below and follow the relevant instructions:**

**To opt-out of Scanbuy’s use of aggregate level and/or anonymous information, as well as any other non-identifying information as described in this Privacy Policy, aside from the primary usage required for the Services to function properly, click** **[here](http://scn.by/9t9ab0htw8lvra)** **.**

If you would like to review the Privacy Policies of our partners, please visit the links below:

**To view inMarket’s Privacy Policy, visit** **[https://inmarket.com/privacy_policy/](https://t.yesware.com/tt/a26d5004bec00d70b6f0376ea7388b2338104c91/1c7cd2323863e3e4d7ffeaf23f1a79fa/bc5229a56f87312e8f611d4ec00f260e/inmarket.com/privacy_policy/)**

**To view Factual’s Privacy Policy, visit** ******<https://www.factual.com/privacy/> **  ****

Some of Scanbuy’s partners provide opt-out tools which are cookie-based.  **If you’d like to opt-out of the services of our customers and/or partners who provide such an opt-out mechanism, but would like to continue using the ScanLife application, please visit the links below and follow the relevant instructions:**

**To opt-out of Oracle’s use of aggregate level and/or anonymous information, visit  ** **<http://www.bluekai.com/privacypolicy.php> ****or  ** **<http://www.bluekai.com/consumers.php#optout> **

**To opt-out of PushSpring’s use of aggregate level and/or anonymous information,  
visit ****<http://www.pushspring.com/optout.html>**********

**You may also opt-out of the collection of aggregate level and/or anonymous information using mechanisms provided by industry groups such as the Network Advertising Initiative (the “NAI”), the Digital Advertising Alliance (the “DAA”) and the European Digital Advertising Alliance (the “eDAA”).**

**To opt-out of the collection of aggregate level and/or anonymous information by NAI members, visit** **<http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>**

**To opt-out of the collection of aggregate level and/or anonymous information by DAA members, visit** ** _<http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>_**

**To opt-out of the collection of aggregate level and/or anonymous information by eDAA members, visit** ** _<http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>_**

**Please note that the opt-out tools discussed above are cookie-based, and only prevent the collection of information pertaining to you on the browser on which they are installed, will only function as described if you browser is set to accept third-party cookies, and may not be as reliable if your cookies are automatically disabled or removed (e.g., some mobile devices and operating systems). If the opt-out cookie is deleted from a browser, the collection of information by participating members will resume until an opt-out cookie is reinstalled on that browser.**

**IX. Transparency and Choice, The Right to be Forgotten  
**Scanbuy cares about your privacy concerns, which may be different for different people. Our goal is to provide you with the information you need to make the most informed choices concerning the information we collect and how it may be used.

When you access the Services, Scanbuy collects your personal information that you provide us, automatically collected information, and retains anonymous and/or anonymized information. Please see **Personal Information** above to learn more about the types of personal information we may collect. Please see **Automatically Collected Information** above to learn more about the types of information we may collect automatically. Please see **Anonymous & Aggregate Information** above to learn more about the anonymous and/or anonymized information that we may retain. If you would like to review what information Scanbuy may have about you, click **[here](http://scn.by/9t9ab0htw8lvre)**. We want to give you the easiest ways to update, amend or delete your information – unless we have to maintain that information for legitimate business or legal purposes. **Scanbuy may be legally required to keep information and not delete it (or to keep information for a certain time, in which case we will comply with any deletion requests only after having fulfilled such requirements).**

If you would like to exercise your Right to be Forgotten, under Article 17 of the GDPR, click **[here](http://scn.by/ks7wutk7nbuth0)**. Scanbuy is committed to protecting the integrity of your information from accidental or malicious destruction. Because of this, we may not delete residual copies of your information, even after you delete

information from the Services, from our active servers or from our backup systems. For clarity, Scanbuy will not delete information that is anonymized and required for the Services to function properly. You can stop the collection of information by uninstalling the application following the standard uninstall processes of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network. ****

**X. External Links  **  
Scanbuy is not liable for any personal information that you submit to third parties or to any website linked to the Site.

**XI. Third Parties**  
Scanbuy is not liable for any information collected, used or disclosed by the user’s mobile device manufacturer or service provider.  Your internet service provider or mobile carrier network may have access to the communications, such as text messages, phone calls or emails, sent using the mobile device.   **For information regarding your service provider’s or carrier’s treatment of your information, please consult their Privacy Policies, which we encourage you to do.**    **If you decide to use third party applications on your device, any information those applications collect may be sent to third parties and this Policy does not apply.   However, third party applications may have their own Privacy Policies that you should review.**

**Scanbuy receives information about consumers from third parties to enable targeted advertising on the website(s) and application(s) that we support. The collection and use of that data is governed by the privacy policy and legal terms of the data collector and the website using the data; it is not governed by Scanbuy and this Policy does not apply.**

**XII. Security**  
Scanbuy is concerned about safeguarding the confidentiality of your information. We provide physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect information we process and maintain.  For example, we limit access to this information to authorized employees and contractors who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our products and services.  Please be aware that, although we endeavor to provide reasonable security for information we process and maintain, no security system can prevent all potential security breaches. ** **

**XIII. Children**  
Scanbuy’s products and services are intended for adult use only and we do not knowingly solicit data from or market to children under the age of 13.  Scanbuy’s products and services are not intended for children, and we ask that minors not submit any personal information to us.  If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with information without their consent, he or she should contact us at [privacy@scanbuy.com](mailto:privacy@scanbuy.com). We will delete such information from our files within a reasonable time.
